ROBERT FARLEY

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Phone: (570)-209-6717 Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/robertfarley89 Email: rfarley89@gmail.com

GitHub: github.com/Nomad-Rob Website: NomadRob.com Location: Tulsa, Oklahoma

SUMMARY

A Software Engineer with a track record of 120+ successful projects and a decade of problem-solving in high-pressure environments. Now transitioning to tech with a project-focused approach. Dedicated to fostering innovation and efficiency in development teams through continuous learning, teamwork and problem-solving.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, React.JS

Backend: Python, Flask, Express, MySQL, MongoDB, Bash, Nodejs

Other Tech: Git/GitHub, Docker, Firebase, Postman, Linux, C Programming, Figma, JSON, REST architecture

PROJECTS

Museum of Imagination (Dec 2023) Team Project

GitHub Repo - https://github.com/Nomad-Rob/Museum_of_the_Imagination

- Led a project for a Christmas-themed virtual exhibit in a 3D Space, coordinating the development of a Three.JS scene, overseeing hosting solutions, and creating an integrated online gift shop.
- Constructed a captivating Three.JS environment as part of the Museum of Imagination's Christmas exhibit, showcasing proficiency in 3D graphics programming and front-end development.

Website Link - https://museum-of-the-imagination.web.app/

Airplane Above (Nov 2023) Solo Project

GitHub Repo - https://github.com/Nomad-Rob/Solo_Hackathon/tree/main/Airplane_Above

- Developed an innovative application utilizing geolocation technology to collect real-time data on the closest aircraft to the user's location, enhancing situational awareness and streamlining decision making processes.
- Utilized an API to gather ADS-B details and show using users location.

Wes's Cozy Kitchen (Sept 2023) Team Project

GitHub Repo - https://github.com/Nomad-Rob/Hack_Sprint-Breakfast

- Contributed to the project as a Database and Game Logic Developer, employing Python and Pygame to craft engaging gameplay mechanics in a breakfast-themed Hacksprint challenge.
- Implemented object-oriented programming practices such as inheritance to create different levels and JSON implementation.

AirBnB Clone (Aug 2023) Team Project

GitHub Repo - https://github.com/Nomad-Rob/holbertonschool-AirBnB_clone_v4

- Programmed a fully functional Airbnb clone web application from scratch, showcasing proficiency in full-stack web development.
- Engineered user authentication, property listing, and booking functionalities, creating an interactive and user-friendly platform.

ROBERT FARLEY

WORK EXPERIENCE

Oklahoma Army National Guard

2006-2023

- UH60M Helicopter Pilot 2020-2023
 - Proficient in diverse aircraft missions including Troop, Movement, Sling Loads, Assault,
 Water Buckets with hundreds of hours in the aircraft.
 - Utilized skills such as Flight Planning, Pre-flight checks, Communication, Navigation, System Management, Emergency Procedures, and Monitor in-flight data.
- Oklahoma Counterdrug Ground Recon Team Leader 2016–2019
 - Led a 6-10 man unit in support of law enforcement with counter narcotic operations in rural and urban environments in Oklahoma in over 100 missions.
 - Served as the subject matter expert for Oklahoma's Ground team in support of law enforcement with participation in over \$45,000,000 seized throughout my tenure.
 - Developed and enforced standardized operating procedures, improving operational efficiency.
- Sniper/Scout Platoon Sergeant 2006–2020
 - Advanced proficiency in using mathematical models and calculations for trajectory prediction, range estimation, and environmental factor analysis.
 - Deployed multiple times, competed in International Joint Service Sniper competitions.
 - Hired, trained, evaluated, and retained high-performing, effective, diverse 32 man team.

Aegis/GardaWorld Federal Services

Designated Defensive Marksman/Protective Security Specialist

2019-2020

- Applied mathematical strategies for mission planning and execution, optimizing operational success through geometric and probabilistic analysis accuracy.
- Conducted pre site surveys on over 25 locations while in a high security posture or low visibility operations.

Xerox Business Solutions Southwest (Apple Contract)

Senior Technical Advisor

2015-2016

- Managed a team of 20 or more personnel to successfully provide exceptional support and resolution to ongoing technical issues while maintaining certain metrics.
- Directly coordinated with iOS and CPU engineers through help desk tickets to provide issue resolution with a 97% resolution rate.

EDUCATION

Atlas School - Anticipated Graduation August 2024

Diploma - Computer Science & Full-Stack Web Development

Rigorous 20-month computer science and software engineering school that is project and peer-learning-based. Student Life Committee - Vice Chair - Represented student interests weekly meetings with school administration.

VOLUNTEERING & LEADERSHIP

Techlahoma

- Volunteered at 2023 ThunderPlains Conference to support the logistics of the check in process for over 200 individuals.
- Involved with setting up Oklahoma's first state-wide Hackathon